# **SMRITI PRASAD**

National Institute of Technology Karnataka, Surathkal (2010-2014)

Email ID: smritip29@gmail.com | +91-8088101366

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/smriti-prasad-2941677b/

Github: https://github.com/smriti29

Multi-faceted UI developer with 5+ years of experience in software development for large-scale firms. Motivated and hardworking, with an ability to meet deadlines and quickly resolve issues. Skilled at team collaboration while working independently in remote environments.

#### **SKILLS**

- Languages: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, C, C++, Java, SQL
- Frameworks and libraries: ReactJs, AngularJs, Jquery, Bootstrap, Django Rest framework
- UI/UX Design Tool: Sketch, InVision
- Data Visualisation Tools: Jasper BI, Tableau
- Others: SASS, JIRA, Jenkins, GIT version control

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# 1. American Express (September 2019 to present): UI/UX developer and designer

Team: Al Labs

Projects: Financial Statement Analyser, Package tracking portal, xLearn, Al Marketplace

Technologies- Reactis, Javascript, HTML, CSS, django rest framework

Roles and responsibilities:

- Requirement Gathering Meeting with the stakeholders to gather requirements and specifications.
- Designing the application Using Sketch integrated with AmEx design Language component.
- Application Development Using **Django** rest framework
- Received Blue Award and certificate in recognition of the contribution made to the team in American Express.

### 2. Barclays (December 2017 to August 2019): UI software developer

**Project name:** Consumer Lending, Digital Mortgages, digital shared services (DSS)

**Technologies**: Javascript, AngularJS, HTML, CSS, Git version control

Roles and responsibilities:

- Development of web pages.
- Consuming RESTful web service.
- Responsible for Build and deployment using Jenkins.
- Maintenance of the existing application familiar with JIRA.
- Received certificate of appreciation in recognition of outstanding contribution to Digital-Barclays UK.
- **3. Wipro Technologies (July 2014 to December 2017):** Recruited under "Wipro Star", a highly selective fast track management development program with an intake from India's premier engineering institutes.

Clients: Bank of New York Mellon, Alcatel Lucent

Technologies: Jasper BI, HTML, CSS, Jquery, Oracle, AngularJs

### Roles and responsibilities:

Developed responsive web pages for displaying information about home device analytics in

a user friendly way.

- Created reports and dashboards (representing summarised information) using **JASPER BI** to be integrated with the webpages.
- Carried out unit testing using Jasmine.
- Received Delivery Excellence Award from Wipro for carrying out the seamless deliveries in time.

# 4. Internships and Projects

• Summer Internship at Phimetrics Technologies, Mumbai,

Projects: Mobile Agents for Android, project tracking web application

Synopsis: Development of an android application for capturing Rx level, phone configuration, signal strength, location, neighbouring cell information and a web application created using PHP, MySql.

• Implemented a single page application for online book shopping (BooKart), demonstrating the function of a cart using AngularJs.

https://smriti29.github.io/Angular apps/BooKart/index.html

Skills: AngularJs, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS.

• Developed a responsive restaurant website at

https://smriti29.github.io/Angular apps/restaurant/index.html

Skills: Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, JQuery.

Developed a quiz game at

https://smriti29.github.io/authorquiz

Skills: ReactJs, HTML, CSS.

#### **EDUCATION**

National Institute of Technology Karnataka, Surathkal (2010-2014)

B. TECH, Information Technology

CGPA: 7.72

Std. XII (C.B.S.E.)

93.4%

Std. X (C.B.S.E.)

95.6%